Matthew Carpenter

Full Stack Software Developer



(520)840-5864



matthew_carpenter@icloud.com



https://linkedin.com/in/matthewcarpenter22



https:/github.com/gethashset



https://matthewcarpenter.herokuapp.com

SKILLS

- MERN (MongoDB, Express, React, Node)
- LAMP (Linux, Apache, Maria, php)
- SCSS / Styled Components
- SQL / noSQL
- Agile / Kanban
- · API(s)
- MVC/FLUX Structure(s)
- Coaching & Development
- AWS S3
- Git
- Unit Testing
- Typescript

KEY COMPETENCIES

- Technical Functional Skills
- Business Acumen
- Intellectual Horsepower



 "Scan this QR code for an easy to share downloadable copy of this resume."

PROFESIONAL SUMMARY



I help people achieve their goals through technology.

Software Engineer and certified systems technician with emphasis on the end user experience. It is my passion to bring projects to life using technology, delivering polished software with both elegance and style. Held a market wide training positions with a focus on adult learning and interpreting data analytics. My experiences have provided me the opportunity to hone my intellectual horsepower without a sacrifice to my soft skills. It is my mission to contribute to a team that develops the world's most cutting edge software.

EXPERIENCE

Madden Media

September 2019 - Current

Frontend Web Developer

At Madden Media — I have the opportunity to work directly with the full stack code base. In this highly visible code-based role I have had the privilege to wear many hats. From code architecture to unit testing web applications proper to deployment. Some of the technology I use daily include: Git, Platform, LAMP, MERN, jQuery, SCSS, javascript libraries, CDN(s), web-scraping and Photoshop. As a member of an Agile team I attend Standups and Scrums to keep all levels of the business informed about application progress. And was even the sole developer on a project that landed one of the largest contracts in Madden Media history.

Apple

April 2011 - October 2019

Genius / ISGT

Apple certified technicians have the privilege to evaluate, isolate, and resolve hardware and software issues at the highest customer facing level. Held the role as a market wide trainer, and even hosted one of the Apple WWDC event. More over, I have had the opportunity to participate with the Siri and Apple Maps teams and work directly with code and development teams.

EDUCATION

Pima Community College

2011-2012

Degree in Progress

Certifications

I ifetime

MERN Stack

Certification and curriculum designed by Trilogy & accredited by the University of Arizona. 2019-2020 (GPA 4.0)

Hardware / Software

ACiT — iOS Service certification.

ACMT — Apple Certified Mac Technician.